In the PCA algorithm we take
在 PCA 算法中
N dimensional features and reduce
我们把n维特征变量
them to some K dimensional feature representation.
降维到k维特征变量
This number K is a parameter
这个数字k
of the PCA algorithm.
是 PCA 算法的一个参数
This number K is also called
这个数字k也被称作
the number of principle components
主成分的数量
or the number of principle components that we've retained.
或者说是我们保留的主成分的数量
And in this video I'd like
在这个视频中
to give you some guidelines,
我会给你们一些参考
tell you about how people
告诉你们
tend to think about how to
人们是怎样思考如何选择
choose this parameter K for PCA.
PCA 的参数k的
In order to choose k,
为了选择参数k
that is to choose the number
也就是要选择主成分的数量
of principal components, here are a couple of useful concepts.
这里有几个有用的概念
What PCA tries to do
PCA 所做的是
is it tries to minimize
尽量最小化
the average squared projection error.
平均平方映射误差 (Average Squared Projection Error)
So it tries to minimize
因此 PCA 就是要将这个量最小化
this quantity, which I'm writing down,
就是我正在写的这个
which is the difference between the
它是原始数据x
projected version, X-approx-i, which
和映射值 x_approx(i) 之间的差
was defined last video, so
这个在上节视频中定义过
it tries to minimize the squared
它就是要最小化
distance between x and it's projection
x和其在低维表面上的映射点
onto that lower dimensional surface.
之间的距离的平方
So that's the average square projection error.
这就是平均平方映射误差
Also let me define the
我还要定义一下
total variation in the
数据的总变差 (Total Variation)
average length squared of
它是这些样本x(i)的
these examples Xi
长度的平方的均值
so the total variation in the
因此数据的总变差
data is the average of
就是我这些训练集中
my training sets of the
每个训练样本长度的
length of each of my training examples.
平均值
And this one says, "On average, how
它的意思是
far are my training examples
“平均来看 我的训练样本
from the vector, from just being all zeros?"
距离零向量多远？
How far is, how far
平均来看
on average are my training examples from the origin?
我的训练样本距离原点多远？”
When we're trying to choose k, a
当我们去选择k值的时候
pretty common rule of thumb
一个常见的
for choosing k is to choose
选择K值的经验法则是
the smaller values so that
选择能够使得它们之间的比例
the ratio between these is less than 0.01.
小于等于0.01的最小的k值
So in other words,
换言之
a pretty common way to
一个非常常用的
think about how we choose k
选择k值的方法是
is we want the average squared projection error.
我们希望平均平方映射误差
That is the average distance
就是x和其映射值之间的
between x and it's projections
平均距离
divided by the total variation of the data.
除以数据的总变差
That is how much the data varies.
就是数据的变化有多大
We want this ratio to be
我们想要这个比值能够
less than, let's say, 0.01.
小于 比如说 0.01
Or to be less than 1%, which is another way of thinking about it.
或者说是小于1% 这是另一种说法
And the way most people think
大部分人在考虑
about choosing K is rather
选择k的方法时
than choosing K directly the
不是直接选择k值
way most people talk about
大部分人所考虑的是
it is as what this
这个数应该是多少
number is, whether it is 0.01
它应该是0.01
or some other number.
还是其它的数
And if it is 0.01, another way
如果是0.01 换言之
to say this to use the
用PCA的语言说就是
language of PCA is that 99% of the variance is retained.
保留了99%的差异性
I don't really want to, don't
我其实并不想
worry about what this phrase
不用担心这短话的学术意义
phrase "99% of variance is retained" just means
这句“保留了99%的差异性”的意思是
that this quantity on the left is less than 0.01.
左边这个数值小于0.01
And so, if you
因此 如果你使用PCA
are using PCA and if you want
并且你想要告诉别人
how many principle components you've
你保留了多少个主成分
retained it would be
更为常见的
more common to say well, I
一种说法是
chose k so that 99% of the variance was retained.
我选择了参数k 使得99%的差异性得以保留
And that's kind of a useful thing
了解这个事情是有用的
to know, it means that you
它的意思是
know, the average squared projection
平均平方映射误差
error divided by the total
除以总变差
variation that was at most 1%.
至多是1%
That's kind of an insightful
这是一个可以去思考的
thing to think about, whereas if
有见解的事情
you tell someone that, "Well I
然而如果你跟别人说
had to 100 principle
“我有100个主成分”
components" or "k was equal
或者说“从1000维的数据中
to 100 in a thousand dimensional
得到的k等于100”
data" it's a little
这就有点
hard for people to interpret
让人难以理解
that.
刚才我说的这些
So this number 0.01 is what people often use.
这个数字0.01就是人们经常用的
Other common values is 0.05,
另一个常用的值是0.05
and so this would be 5%,
那么这就会是5%
and if you do that then
如果是这样的话
you go and say well 95%
你可以说
of the variance is
95%的差异性被保留了
other numbers maybe 90% of the variance is
还有其它数值 比如90%的差异性被保留了
retained, maybe as low as 85%.
还有低到85%的
So 90% would correspond to say
因此90%对应的是0.10
0.10, kinda 10%.
也就是10%
And so range of values
取值范围是
from, you know, 90, 95,
90 95 99
99, maybe as low as 85% of
也可能低到保留85%的差异性
the variables contained would be a fairly typical range in values.
这些都是比较典型的取值范围
Maybe 95 to 99
可能从95到99
is really the most
是人们最为
common range of values that people use.
常用的取值范围
For many data sets you'd be
对于许多数据集
surprised, in order to retain
你可能会惊讶
99% of the variance, you can
为了保留99%的差异性
often reduce the dimension of
通常你可以大幅地降低数据的维度
the data significantly and still retain most of the variance.
却还能保留大部分的差异性
Because for most real life
因为大部分现实中的数据
data says many features are
许多特征变量
just highly correlated, and so
都是高度相关的
it turns out to be possible
所以实际上
to compress the data a
大量压缩数据是可能的
lot and still retain you
而且仍然会保留
know 99% of the variance
99%或95%的差异性
or 95% of the variance. So how do you implement this?
那么你该如何实现它呢？
Well, here's one algorithm that you might use.
你可能会用到这个算法
You may start off, if you
你可以这样开始
want to choose the value of
比如你想选取k的值
k, we might start off with k equals 1.
我们可以从k=1开始
And then we run through PCA.
然后我们再进行主成分分析
You know, so we compute, you
我们算出
reduce, compute z1, z2, up to zm.
Ureduce z(1) z(2) 一直到 z(m)
Compute all of those x1
算出所有那些
approx and so on up to xm approx
x_approx(1) 一直到 x_approx(m)
and then we check if 99% of the variance is retained.
然后我们看一下99%的差异性是否被保留下来了
Then we're good and we use k equals 1.
是的话就搞定了 我们就用 k=1
But if it isn't then what we'll do we'll next try K equals 2.
但如果不是 那么我们接下来尝试 k=2
And then we'll again
然后我们要重新走一遍
run through this entire procedure and
这整个过程
check, you know is this expression satisfied.
检查是否满足这个表达式
Is this less than 0.01. And if not then we do this again.
这个式子的值是否小于0.01 如果不是 我们再重复一次
Let's try k equals 3,
我们尝试 k=3
then try k equals 4,
然后试 k=4 以此类推
and so on until maybe
一直试到
we get up to k equals
比如我们一直试到 k=17
17 and we find 99% of
然后发现99%的数据
the data have is retained and then
都被保留了
we use k equals 17, right?
我们就会用 k=17
That is one way
这是一种用来选择
to choose the smallest value
使得99%的差异性能够得以保留的
of k, so that and 99% of the variance is retained.
最小的k值的方法
But as you can imagine,
但是可以想见
this procedure seems horribly inefficient
这个过程的效率相当地低
we're trying k equals one, k equals two, we're doing all these calculations.
我们在尝试 k=1  k=2 时 做了所有这些计算
Fortunately when you implement
幸好 你在应用 PCA 时
PCA it actually, in
实际上 在这一步
this step, it actually gives us
它已经给了我们
a quantity that makes it
一个可以使计算变得
much easier to compute these things as well.
容易很多的量
Specifically when you're calling
特别是当你调用
SVD to get these
svd 来计算这些
matrices u, s, and d,
矩阵U S V时
when you're calling usvd on the
当你对协方差的矩阵 Sigma
covariance matrix sigma, it also
调用 svd 时
gives us back this matrix
我们还会得到
S and what
这个矩阵S
S is, is going to
S是一个正方形矩阵
be a square matrix an N by N matrix in fact,
实际上是一个 n×n 的矩阵
that is
它是一个
diagonal.
对角矩阵
So is diagonal entries s one
对角线上的元素是
one, s two two, s
s11 s22 s33 一直到 snn
three three down to s
S11 S22 S33 一直到 Snn
n n are going to
它们是矩阵中
be the only non-zero elements of
仅有的非零元素
this matrix, and everything off
对角以外的其他元素
the diagonals is going to be zero.
都是0
Okay?
明白吗？
So those big O's that I'm drawing,
所以我写的这些巨大的零
by that what I mean is
就代表我所说的
that everything off the diagonal
这个矩阵中对角以外的
of this matrix all of those
其他元素
entries there are going to be zeros.
所有这些元素都等于0
And so, what is possible
可以证明的是
to show, and I won't prove
我不会在此证明
this here, and it turns out
实际上
that for a given value of
对于一个给定的k值
k, this quantity
这边的这个量
over here can be computed much more simply.
可以更容易地算出来
And that quantity can be computed
那个数值可以通过这个式子计算出来
as one minus sum from
1减去
i equals 1 through
从 i=1 到 k 对 Sii 求和
sum from I equals 1
除以 从 i=1 到 n 对 Sii 求和
So just to say that it words, or
这个的意思是
just to take another
或者说从另一个角度来解释它
if K equals 3 let's say.
假如说 k=3
What we're going to do to
我们接下来要
compute the numerator is sum
计算的分子是
from one--  I equals 1
从 i=1 到 3 对 Sii 求和
compute the sum of these first three elements.
就是算出这前三个元素的和
So that's the numerator.
这就是分子
And then for the denominator, well that's
然后计算分母
the sum of all of these diagonal entries.
分母是这些对角元素的总和
And one minus the ratio of
1减去这个比例
that, that gives me this
就是这里的这个值
quantity over here, that I've
就是这个我用
circled in blue.
蓝色圈起来的数字
And so, what we can do
接下来我们要做的就是
is just test if this
看一下这个数字
is less than or equal to 0.01.
是否小于等于0.01
Or equivalently, we can test
或者等价的 我们可以查看
if the sum from
从 i=1 到 k 对 Sii 求和
divided by sum from i
除以 从 i=1 到 n 对 Sii 求和
if this is greater than or
它是否大于等于0.99
want to be sure that 99% of the variance is retained.
如果你想确保能够保留99%的差异性的话
And so what you can do
所以你要做的
is just slowly increase k,
就是慢慢地增大k值
set k equals one, set k equals
把k值设为1 k值设为2
two, set k equals three and so
把k值设为3 以此类推
on, and just test this quantity
并检验这个数值
to see what is the
找出能够确保99%的差异性被保留的最小的k值
And if you do
如果这样做
this, then you need to call
那么你只需要调用
the SVD function only once.
一次 svd 函数
Because that gives you the
因为它会给你S矩阵
S matrix and once you
一旦有了S矩阵
have the S matrix, you can
你便可以
then just keep on doing
通过增加分子上的k值
the value of K in the
来做这个计算
numerator and so you
因此你就不用
don't need keep to calling SVD over
一遍一遍地调用 svd 函数
and over again to test out the different values of K.
来检验不同的k值
So this procedure is much more
因此这一步非常高效
efficient, and this can
它能够让你
allow you to select the
不用一遍一遍地
value of K without needing
从头运行 PCA
to run PCA from scratch
就能选择k值
over and over. You just run SVD once, this
你只要运行一次 svd 函数
gives you all of these diagonal numbers,
就能得到所有的对角数值
all of these numbers S11, S22 down to SNN,
所有这些数值 S11 S22 一直到 Snn
and then you can
然后你就可以
just you know, vary K
改变这个式子中的k值
in this expression to find
来找到能够保留99%的差异性
that 99% of the variance is retained.
的最小的k值
So to summarize, the way
来总结一下
that I often use, the
我在使用 PCA 进行压缩时
way that I often choose K
通常采用的决定k值的方法是
is I would call SVD once
对协方差矩阵
in the covariance matrix, and then
调用一次 svd 函数
I would use this formula and
然后用这个公式
pick the smallest value of
来找出满足这个表达式的
K for which this expression is satisfied.
最小的k值
And by the way, even if you
顺便说一下
were to pick some different value
即使你要挑选一些不同的k值
of K, even if you were
即使你要
to pick the value of K
手动挑选k值
manually, you know maybe you
也许你有
have a thousand dimensional data
1000维的数据
and I just want to choose K equals one hundred.
我只想要 k=100
Then, if you want to explain
如果你想要向别人
to others what you just did,
解释你所做的
a good way to explain the performance
向他们解释
of your implementation of PCA to
你实现的 PCA 的性能
them, is actually to take
的一个好方法
this quantity and compute what
实际上是这个数值
this is, and that will
把它算出来
tell you what was the percentage of variance retained.
它会告诉你百分之多少的差异性被保留了下来
And if you report that number, then,
如果你把这个数值展现出来
you know, people that are familiar
那么熟悉 PCA 的人们
with PCA, and people can
就可以通过它
use this to get a
来更好地理解
good understanding of how well
你用来代表原始数据的
your hundred dimensional representation is
100维数据
approximating your original data
近似得有多好
set, because there's 99% of variance retained.
因为有99%的差异性被保留了
That's really a measure of your
这就是一个平方投影误差的测量指标
ratio being 0.01, just
这个比值是0.01
gives people a good intuitive
就会让别人对你实现的 PCA
sense of whether your implementation
是否对原始数据做了一个好的近似
good approximation of your original data set.
有一个很好的直观感受
So hopefully, that gives you
希望对你来说
an efficient procedure for choosing
这是一个选择k值的
the number K. For choosing
有效的过程
what dimension to reduce your
这就是如何选择
data to, and if
要将数据降低到什么维度
you apply PCA to very
如果你将 PCA 应用于
high dimensional data sets, you know, to like
很高维的数据集
a thousand dimensional data, very often,
常见的 比如一千维的数据
just because data sets tend
因为数据集的特征变量
to have highly correlated
通常有较高的相关性
features, this is just a
这其实是常见的
property of most of the data sets you see,
大部分数据集的一个特性
you often find that PCA
你经常会发现
will be able to retain ninety nine
PCA 能够保留
per cent of the variance or say,
99%的差异性
ninety five ninety nine, some
或者说95%的差异性
high fraction of the variance,
或者某些高百分比的差异性
even while compressing the data
即使在压缩很大比例的数据的情况下
by a very large factor.
也会看到这样的现象 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：星星之火 校对：竹二个 审核：所罗门捷列夫